The Vulnerable People Project stands in
solidarity with the most vulnerable
people in the world when the world has
walked away.
In Lebanon, in Gaza, in the West Bank,
in the Nuba Mountains of Sudan, in
Ukraine,
in Afghanistan and Pakistan,
the Vulnerable People Project is there
serving vulnerable Christians,
vulnerable Catholics. We have guards
right now in front of synagogues,
mosques, and churches.
We are committed to defending vulnerable
communities from violence, to stand with
ethnic and religious minorities that are
facing genocide. And if you want to be a
part of our team, go to our website
vulnerablepeopleproject.com,
look around,
and click on the button in the upper
right and become a monthly donor. It's
the monthly donors that give us the
ability to do all the great work that we
do. Also, we have a new campaign, Save
West Bank Christians, and it's at
savewestbankchristians.com.
The state of Israel is using Zionist
settlers, terrorist settlers, as proxies
defended by the IDF as they're
ethnically cleansing the oldest
Christian community in the world, the
Christian communities in Taybeh, and
Beit Sahour, and Bethlehem, and
Bethlehem, the birthplace of Jesus
Christ. We may see in the coming years
the last Christian leave, but we're
committed to making sure that doesn't
happen. So, go to
savewestbankchristians.com.
Now on to my interview
with the great John Kiriakou. Welcome to
the show.
>> Thank you for having me. Brother, first
of all, I just want to say, you know,
when I first met you it was through a
good friend of ours, Jason, who is an
incredible writer and a brilliant man
and a good man.
>> And when I met you, I was with my
filmmaking partner,
and we were just both really in awe.
And we just talked about you. You know,
and and
and we're just like, this guy is
interest- cuz
when I first met you, I thought, first
of all, you're striking and unassuming
at the same time.
You were kind
and joyful,
but I could see that you were addled
with pain.
The other thing that was really evident
was that you had a very
deep relationship with God.
And so Jenny and I, we were just talking
and like and we were just talking about
all that you've gone through. And now
the world knows because I found out from
my sons, cuz I'm in my own little world,
that you are literally the most famous
guy in the world of Gen Z right now.
>> Things went kind of crazy the last 3
weeks. Yeah, it's wild.
>> Inexplicably.
It just happened. Like literally
overnight. I woke up one morning, my
niece called me and she said, "Uncle
John, you're the most famous man on the
internet right now." I said, "Why?"
Like how's today different from
yesterday? Yeah, they they figured out
my my son said, "Does he think he even
knows how famous he is?" I go, "I think
he probably figured it out." So you
figured it out.
>> it out. And I'm glad. You know, I'm glad
that young people have discovered you
because you're you're what you know, you
what you have to say is very important
to their future because this generation
we have been thoughtless
to their future in a way that I don't
think any other generation has been
orphaned.
They've been orphaned by the baby
boomers, they've been orphaned by Gen X.
They have an antagonistic relationship
with millennials. They call all of us
boomers. I think millennials and up to
them are boomers.
>> Right. And then there are a lot of these
calloused uh they call them muscular
Christians or these muscular
conservative activists, which
I found
not they're not good mentors. They might
say a lot of sensible things, but
overall they're not someone I would want
my children to look up to. I said, "We
don't need muscular Christians, we need
calloused men with calloused hands
to be influential on young people, but
men with calloused hands generally
aren't making Tik Tok videos.
>> Yeah.
But here you are just for the all the
interviews you've been doing over the
years, other people are taking them,
cutting them up.
>> That's what's happened. And so finally
you're the first calloused hands
influencer maybe in the history of the
world. Crazy.
But I'll take it. If if it can allow me
to reach young people who are going
going to end up leading the CIA, the
FBI, the State Department, the Defense
Department one of these days, then it's
time well spent. I I I think so. So what
do you think when you hear me say that
like
when I met you and I think a lot of
people probably see this, you're kind,
you're joyful, you're friendly, you're
attentive.
But you can't hide like the pain.
I I have always been a glass half full
kind of guy.
I'm
if anything overly optimistic most of
the time.
But um you know, life's not been easy.
It's not been easy.
>> Yeah.
You know, I've I've
I've learned only recently that there is
a newly recognized condition that
psychiatrists are dealing with
uh with patients called moral injury.
And it's not just
it's not just a psychic injury for
having done something.
It's a psychic injury from having
witnessed something or from having not
been able to prevent something.
And that's real.
Moral injury is real.
It's almost a form of PTSD.
You just can't get over it.
You know, my sort of heyday as a CIA
counterterrorism officer
was almost 25 years ago.
And I still relive it every single day.
Every single day in my mind.
And it's not good.
I I have pictures
I don't know why I don't delete them,
but I have pictures from those days that
would make your hair stand up.
It was an ugly time.
Yeah, I think when there's a lot of
these influencers that are in the same
space where you're talking from,
when I hear them, like, I don't feel
that they actually did much.
Because I don't see that moral injury.
And with the work that I do with VPP, we
witness a lot of very sorrowful things.
I was in Iraq with the Peshmerga, the
war against ISIS. I've been in Sudan
during the genocide, involved in the
evacuation of Afghans.
And it and it's
it wounds you. It humbles you. It makes
you repulsed by violence.
>> Mhm. I can't smell stand the smell of
cordite. Mhm.
>> I pretend to like hunting for my sons.
Um
can you tell us when was the first time
you must have started as a young,
patriotic, hopeful
man.
When was the first time that you
realized there was a tension between
your values and what you were asked to
do? Do you Would you remember that
moment?
>> the date.
You remember the date?
>> May the 6th, 2002.
A long time into your career, huh? Well
into my career. I had convinced myself
that we were the good guys.
And sure, we made mistakes, but we were
the good guys. We were on the side of
righteousness and freedom and, you know,
all these wonderful attributes.
And I was uh I've told this story many
times, but I was in the um
the sandwich line in the CIA cafeteria.
And uh one of my colleagues came up to
me and said, "Oh, very casually." He
says, "Oh, I'm so glad I ran into you.
Would you like to be certified in the
use of enhanced interrogation
techniques?"
I said, "What's that mean?" I had never
heard that term before.
And he goes, "We're going to start
getting rough with these guys."
And I said, "What does that mean?"
And then he described these techniques
to me. I said, "Mhm, buddy, I said, that
sounds like a torture program to me."
And he said, "It's not a torture
program. The president said we could do
it and it was approved by DOJ." And I
said, "Yeah, let me think about it for
an hour." I walked out of the sandwich
line. I went up to the seventh floor,
the executive floor of the CIA. It was a
very, very senior CIA officer for whom I
had worked in the Middle East 10 years
earlier. And um and I knocked on his
door. I didn't have an appointment or
anything. And I said, "I need some
advice. I was just asked if I wanted
certified in these enhanced
interrogation techniques.
I said, "It sounds like a torture
program to me. What do you think?"
And he said, "First of all, let's call a
spade a spade." He said, "This is a
torture program.
They can use whatever euphemism they
want, but it's a torture program. And
torture is a slippery slope." He said,
"You know how these guys are. Half of
them are cowboys and somebody's going to
go too far and they're going to kill a
prisoner. And when that happens, there's
going to be a congressional
investigation and then there's going to
be a Justice Department investigation
and somebody's going to go to prison. Do
you want to go to prison?" And I said,
"No, I don't want to go to prison."
And I was the only one who went to
prison at the end of the day.
But I went back downstairs and I said,
"This is a torture program and I want no
part of it." I said, "I have a a moral
and ethical problem with it and I
believe that it's illegal. I don't care
what DOJ says."
I was actually passed over for promotion
2 weeks later. I had just captured Abu
Zubaydah with these two hands.
The highest ranking
uh counterterrorism capture
in the war on terror at the time.
And I was passed over for promotion and
my boss told me that the director of
counterterrorism said that I had
displayed a shocking lack of commitment
to counterterrorism because I was the
only one who refused to be trained in
the torture uh program.
So,
that
big shot on the seventh floor, when he
realized I was not on the promotion
list, he promoted me with a stroke of of
his pen. But, I realized, "Hmm,
this is a problem, and it's going to be
a bigger problem, and I'm standing alone
on this." I had another friend at the
CIA. We were in the Counterterrorism
Center together. We're both Greek
American.
We're both CIA officers. He also
happened to be a general and
Brigadier General in the army and a
psychiatrist.
Talk about an overachiever.
But, he said to me one day,
"Buddy, uh you know, behind your back,
they call you the human rights guy."
And I said, I said, "I don't care. I
I've heard it. I don't care." He said,
"You know that's not a compliment,
right?"
And I said, "Steve,
I'm right,
and they're wrong."
And I left it at that.
But, I realized that day, the day that
they approached me, this was going to be
a fight and I was going to have to do it
alone. I mean, we're fighting a war, we
were told for human rights.
>> Right.
And they're using the human rights guy
is You would even think somewhere in
your chain of command, they would admire
you for it, even if they recognized they
had to do what they had to do, but they
would say that there's a place for this
man in the organization. And like you
like your boss said call a spade a
spade. You would think in I was a scout
in the military, we were told never
misrepresent what you say what you see.
That's right. So, you would think at
CIA, if I'm just a line platoon
infantryman, and we are drilled to say
what you see.
Don't say what you think you If you felt
what don't say what you felt, don't say
what you thought, you say what you write
down what seven tanks, 120 men.
You would think that at CIA, calling a
spade a spade would be drilled into
everyone. You would think.
And that wasn't it at all. You know,
it's funny,
at the time,
there were fewer than two dozen people
in the whole of the US government who
knew about this torture program.
>> Less than two dozen.
In the entire US government.
And now they just let me in on the
secret and I said, "Oh, no, that's
illegal, immoral, and unethical."
I'm going to be a problem for them.
Mhm. So, later on when I when I blew the
whistle in December of 2007
I got a I got an email from a retired
deputy director of the CIA.
And he said, I saved it as a souvenir.
He said, "You've chosen a difficult
path.
I'm glad somebody did.
I only wish that it had been me."
Which is nice.
I wish it had been him, too. Yeah. But
you know, I realized then that I
actually wasn't alone.
You know, maybe people weren't willing
to say things
publicly
but I I wasn't alone.
What would you say to young
intelligence officers today
who are in a similar dilemma? There are
There must be, right? Right now, there's
someone right now.
>> And and they're in a in a similar
dilemma. They're facing similar dilemmas
as you were facing.
>> Yeah.
And they feel alone.
Their career's on the line. They could
look at prison time. What would you tell
them? Two things, one philosophical and
one practical. Philosophically we all
know in our guts the difference between
right and wrong. We've known it since we
were children.
Do the right thing.
You know what the right thing is.
Just do it. Right? It's not worth
50 years of PTSD
and and wondering exactly how much blood
is on your hands. Do the right thing.
From a practical perspective, though, I
would say
don't say a word until your lawyer is
sitting in the chair next to you. Is
that the mistake you made?
>> That's the mistake I made. I had to be
reactive instead of proactive. I went on
ABC News and I said the CIA is torturing
its prisoners, that torture is official
US government policy, and that the
policy had been personally approved by
the president, and the whole government
fell on my head.
I really wish I had had a lawyer sitting
next to me.
Now, what would you say to like I have a
wife, I have a mortgage, I have children
to put through school. Like I want to do
the right thing, but I can't. Yeah, it's
not an easy decision. I had a wife and
five children and a mortgage and and I
did it anyway. Now, I will say
that from one perspective I blew it,
right? I lost everything. I lost my
freedom, I lost my pension, I lost my
job, I lost my family.
Um my wife and I split up. That's the
thorn in your side. That's the pain we
see.
But
you really get to see
who your friends really are.
I
That person
that person that I was married to was
not the person I thought I was married
to.
And
I realize now that
life, God
did me a favor
by exposing to me just who my friends
were and weren't. I had family members.
I had one cousin walk away from me
saying
listen, he said, "Cuz I can't talk to
you anymore.
You brought shame to our family." And I
said, "I brought shame to our family?
You imported cocaine for the Colombians.
And I brought shame to our family?"
That's the cousin that had a problem
with what you did.
>> Yeah, I was like, "Dude, you're doing me
a favor. I never really liked you
anyway."
That's what you find out, right? The
people you lose, you real you know,
there's a a friend of mine told me this
this analogy of greyhounds. They chase
this mechanical rabbit their whole life,
but every once in a while a greyhound
will capture it'll catch the mechanical
rabbit. It bites it, cuts itself, it
bleeds,
and it will never race again because it
realizes it was chasing a lie.
He said you feel sorry for that
greyhound cuz it can never race again.
It's injured, but no, it's free from an
illusion from a a life of an illusion.
So what you're saying is that this
snapped you out of a life that was an
illusion. That's exactly what it was. It
was an illusion.
And now I sleep beautifully at night. I
like myself.
You know, I think I wasn't meant to be
in that marriage after all. I thought I
was deeply in love, had a wonderful
marriage. I guess I didn't.
Not really.
I had fooled myself into it. And you
know,
there was a bigger
there was a bigger reason for doing all
this. I probably didn't realize it at
the time,
but it was to influence another
generation of of people.
And so I've embraced it. You know,
Daniel Ellsberg, the the Godfather of
all national security whistleblowers,
Dan Dan leaked the Pentagon Papers in
1970 or 71. And the Nixon administration
threw everything it had at him. They
even broke into his psychiatrist's
office and released his psychiatric
records to the press. That's why he Dan
was never
charged with espionage because
the Nixon administration sent the
plumbers in to to you know, steal his
medical records.
So Dan said something to me once. When I
when I
when I was just leaving for prison, it
was just a few days before I went to
prison.
And he said,
um
"If there's one thing that is consistent
across all whistleblowers,
it's that we never make a financial
comeback.
Never."
And I said, "Dan, that won't be me."
If they thought they were going to
silence me, they didn't know me at all.
I'm going to embrace this.
And I did. People say, "Oh, you leaked."
Yes.
And I would do it again today if I had
the opportunity. Mel Gibson calls that
you hug the cactus.
>> That's right.
That's exactly what it is. Bring it. I I
gave an interview My first interview
when I got out of prison was to the BBC.
It's their version of 60 Minutes, but
it's very uh combative.
And I knew it was.
Uh Cross Talk, maybe? I forget exactly
the name of the of the show. But anyway,
partway through it,
the host was getting frustrated with me.
And he said, "You are not apologetic at
all. You're not showing any remorse.
You're not showing any contrition." And
I said, "No. I'm not because I don't
apologize."
>> You should be remorseful. You should
show contrition.
>> do it again.
I would do it again today, and I would
go straight back to prison, and I would
embrace that, too. So, no. If you If you
thought I was going to come on your show
and apologize and say, "Oh, woe is me. I
should have kept my mouth shut." No.
That's never going to happen.
You must have read Cyrano de Bergerac as
a kid. You know, I wonder these people
are so dishonorable that when they meet
an honorable person, they're shocked.
They don't know what is going What is
going on here? You don't fear prison?
Seneca wrote that if you don't fear
calumny, death, or poverty, you are
free.
There it is. Somebody sent me a copy of
Dostoevsky's uh A Day in the Life of
Ivan
Denisovich when I was in prison. And I
thought, "Oh, I'm not sure
>> That is a sorrowful book.
>> dark.
>> I tried to read it 10 times. I can't get
far into it.
>> I I got through it in a day. I read the
whole thing in a day. It's not terribly
long, but it's very rough. You were like
>> were like, "Oh, I found someone that had
it worse than me."
>> In fact, that was the conclusion. My
conclusion was, "Well, at least they're
not starving us." That's why you read
it. It was making you happy. You're
like, "Wow, It's like, "It's so so
great. It's so cold. My teeth are
chattering. I think I may die before the
morning. Yeah,
it's cold like that here, too. Yeah.
>> Yeah, but at least they're not starving
us."
Oh my gosh. I mean, the food's not
great. What I really wanted to talk to
you about
was, you know, we're born here We're
born here to leave here. Mhm. We were
created for eternity.
The end of the day, so many people are
just trapped here.
But we were made to spend eternity with
God, and you're Greek Orthodox.
>> Mhm.
And I have to imagine, like most people
from Orthodox churches, I'm Catholic.
There's a period in our childhood where
we take our faith maybe as seriously as
we take our cultural identity.
>> Yes. Um
Can you I want to know like how did all
of this Like you went through
everything.
Everything. And I hope you don't mind me
saying it. I mean, you went through
being betrayed by your country. You
know, you wrote Hannah Arendt is someone
who I greatly admire. She was betrayed
by everyone she loved. Her Heidegger was
her lover. She loved Germany. She loved
Western philosophy. She was betrayed by
everything she loved. Like Dreyfus.
Yeah.
>> Went through the same thing. And you
went through this. You were betrayed by
an organization that you gave your life
to, a country that you loved, a woman
that you loved. Um
When did your faith I have to imagine
there came a point where it
it went from maybe being just cultural
or subconscious, like your decision.
When you made your deci-
When did faith get front-shelved for
you? When did your relationship with God
come to the forefront? Or was it always
there?
It was pretty much always there, and I
will say that I I never doubted my faith
through this whole thing. I remember
being angry with God for a little while
and saying I remember like saying out
loud,
"Am I really that bad of a person that I
deserve this? Like really? Cuz I can
name people that I think are worse than
I am. But I'm that bad."
>> you say that? This is after my arrest
but before my incarceration.
I just couldn't understand why this was
happening.
>> sitting in a jail cell.
No, I I was out in a day
and and was back home. Like really? I
really deserve this.
And I remember my wife saying, "This has
to be some kind of a test." I had that
one angry conversation with God.
I end up going to prison and thinking,
"All I have really is my faith." The
only thing they allow you to bring in is
uh is a Bible. That's it.
Or a Quran, whatever you happen to have.
Can you bring in a rosary or prayer
beads?
>> No, you can buy those through the chapel
once you get there.
Um and so I worked for a few weeks in
the library. I hated it. I hated the
prison guards. They were just monsters
and criminals themselves.
And I mean that in quite Is that on
drugs?
>> the literal, sorry. I mean that in the
literal sense of the word. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah, just bad in every way. And so I
transferred to the chapel.
I liked the chaplain. He was actually
the only prison official there that I I
genuinely liked and respected. He was
he was there only because he wanted to
do the right thing
and he realized
it just swallowed him up.
So I got a job in the chapel, working in
the chapel library, and realized
immediately there are no books on
Orthodoxy.
There There's a huge section on
Catholicism. There's a The biggest
section, of course, of course, is
Protestantism, Islam, Judaism.
Um
There were There was a shelf on
Mormonism.
The pagans had
>> there are a lot of Mormons in prison.
There were a handful, and they were all
tax cheats.
>> Financial crimes. Yeah. Yeah, exactly.
It was all financial crimes. All of them
Every one of them. Yeah. So, um
So, I wrote to a priest in um nearby
Johnstown, Pennsylvania.
Immediately,
he starts sending books, like lots of
books. And then he starts
>> Seraphim Rose was Oh my god, it was
Church Fathers, The The Desert Fathers,
uh biographies of saints, um a
four-volume encyclopedia of the saints,
uh just fantastic, The Orthodox Study
Bible, which includes the Apocrypha.
Fantastic stuff.
>> Yeah.
And so, I was able to build a good
collection
of Orthodox books. The The only problem
I ran into, there was only one other
Orthodox prisoner in the prison. He was
Ukrainian Orthodox, but he was a
pedophile. Age difference.
>> Yeah, so I I was on my own. I had a
personal policy
>> Yeah, no, no. Right. So,
I I found
refuge in that
uh chapel. Now, it's not
the kind of chapel that you might be
imagining. It's just kind of a
you know, a room.
Just an an empty room.
>> filled with icons
>> not filled with icons
and you have to go in there and shoo all
shoo away all these guys that are having
sex in there because they knew the
cameras weren't working.
>> Oh my gosh.
>> And then And then it's a It's a safe
haven for pedophiles because they're not
allowed to remain in their cells because
their cellmates will beat them if they
remain in.
They're not allowed in the TV room.
They'll get a beating. They're afraid to
go outside to the yard, they'll get a
beating. And so the only place they can
go during the day is either the chapel
or the library. So the library is all
pedophiles, and then the chapel's all
pedophiles. So that was an ongoing
problem.
What are you going to do? So
>> So I made the best of it. So you were
already a
deeply into your faith.
So as an intelligence officer, did it
come to your mind a lot? Like when it
when um
I have to imagine loving your enemy,
which we're commanded to do as
Christians.
>> That But that took me some time.
>> How And I'm not talking about the people
that betrayed you in our own government,
but when you are going after terrorists,
they're our enemies.
>> Well, you know what?
>> get to know them well. You get to know
everything about them. I sat with Abu
Zubaydah for 56 consecutive hours. I was
practically delirious from from fatigue.
But I remember telling him, I was
sitting in a chair at the foot of his
bed. He was tied to the bed. I tied him
to the bed because I was afraid I was
going to fall asleep and he would escape
somehow. There he was not going to
escape. He was shot and almost almost
killed.
But I said to him,
"I should hate you.
I should want to kill you.
And I don't."
I said, "You're pathetic." He was only
in his 20s. Yeah. And
and I was like,
"You're the fearsome Al-Qaeda?
You're what we're so terrified of?
You're pathetic."
And I
I couldn't hate him.
And I It's funny, I almost wanted to.
When I was leaving
>> Could you We're commanded to love our
enemy, which is it's hard, obviously. I
can't
>> I I can't even love people that don't
like me.
>> Yeah.
And even if they've never wronged me.
Like what, they don't like me? Ugh.
So there's one one person in my life who
wronged me more than anybody else ever
could have.
And a person that she became
close to.
And it took me years
to get to the point where I could
forgive them.
And then I sought him out. They They
didn't work as a pair.
I sought him out.
And I scared the hell out of him when I
called him.
I was visiting his country.
And I said, "Don't worry.
I'm not here to harm you.
I just wanted to tell you I've thought
about this a lot.
And I forgive you."
And he said, "Really?" And I said,
"Really. You shouldn't have done what
you did. That was wrong.
But I forgive you."
And he said, "Well, thank you."
And I said, "You're welcome." And I
don't know How do you think he
understood it from his worldview? I
think he probably didn't give a
whether or not I forgave him or not. But
that's okay, too.
Because I felt better. You know, we
forgive for ourselves.
If the person being forgiven
accepts the forgiveness and is gracious
about it, great. Good on them.
But I did it for myself.
It just took me a long time to get
there.
How did But did working as a CIA officer
did it change how you understand it? Did
it make it easier or harder for you to
love our enemies?
You know, the culture
>> And I have to share with you this was a
question from a friend of mine.
Yeah. And she she I guess this is
something she's
wrestling with. It made it harder. The
culture is such that
the culture is such that they can't risk
us loving our enemies.
We need to be willing at the drop of a
hat to kill our enemies.
And thank God I was never in that
position. But you're trained to be.
And um
I think that it would not benefit the
program
if you're out there forgiving people.
Yeah.
>> The day that I was leaving for Pakistan
I only had
>> I guess you can love and forgive people
that have to be killed. I guess you can.
Sure.
But it's it's a mystery for us to even
kind of wrap our minds around.
>> It is. It's very difficult. The The day
that I was leaving for Pakistan and I
only had 24 hours notice, right? I went
to the office just to say goodbye to
everybody. But you know, the director of
counterterrorism at the time said, "On
9/11
all of us are going to have to do our
part. Not all of us are going to make it
home."
So
if you want to walk now,
nobody will think less of you. Nobody
budged.
And I knew what the risks were going
overseas into an active war zone.
And then specifically doing
counterterrorism operations. So I went
to the office to say goodbye to
everybody. Just in case, you know, it
was the last goodbye.
And my boss came up to me and and he
gave me a hug. And as he's hugging me,
he whispers to me "Kill them all."
And I said, "Really, John?
Are we there already?"
And then he shook my hand.
And I walked out. It's like, "Wow." Cuz
already
that
that emotion had never even occurred to
me.
Not until he said it.
>> As young infantrymen, we had that we
talked that way. Yeah.
>> But you expect 19-year-old infantrymen
to talk that way.
>> Sure. But not a not a 55-year-old at the
time and seasoned intelligence veteran.
>> Yeah.
And I I thought about that the whole way
over.
Like, jeez, I I want to do the right
thing. I want to capture as many of
these guys as I can and bring them to
trial so that they face punishment for
for the terrible crimes that they've
committed against the American people.
But just killing them in cold blood had
never even occurred to me.
Why would it have? We're a nation of
laws.
Right? We've got a constitution.
>> what we're fighting for.
>> That's right. That's what we're fighting
for. Exactly.
In fact,
and forgive me if if you've heard this
>> Well, here's this and our faith teaches
us something that that's very important.
We never do evil that good would come of
it.
And once you throw that away, there's no
limits. Yeah.
That's right.
What was it like How did you keep your
moral grounding when you're you're
recruiting people?
You're building relationships with them.
You have to deceive them.
Yeah, see, well, that's a good question.
I It's because I genuinely believed we
were the good guys. And I wasn't taking
advantage of anybody.
I was putting them at risk, of course,
but
they went into this with their eyes
open.
You know, I remember my one of my
station chiefs coming up to me
saying,
"I've been doing this for 25 years, and
I'm good at it."
He said, "In my 25 years, I've recruited
nine people."
He said, "You've been here 2 years,
and you've recruited five people."
And I thought he was kind of kidding
around, and I said, "And not a safe
house keeper among them." Which is kind
of the cheap entry-level recruitment,
like you just go up to some old lady,
usually an American, and say, "Hey,
listen, you know, I'm with the State
Department. If I pay you 500 a month,
would you rent an apartment for me, and
I'll pay everything?"
Yeah, and that kind of counts as a
recruitment, but it's an ongoing joke in
the CIA.
Yeah, it shouldn't count as a
recruitment. I was recruiting
killers,
bombers, terrorists,
people that you wouldn't trust, you
know, with your family.
But um but I really believed we were the
good guys. And so
>> necessary for you to be good at
recruiting?
>> Absolutely.
If I If I didn't believe in myself and
the mission, I I had have failed.
Did there used to be a point like
I call it method activism where I have
to build a relationship with somebody
and
they are gaslighting me, but I
absolutely
convince myself that they're sincere.
Does that make sense?
So that I can influence them more
effectively?
Did you Did Did you ever have that sort
of where you
Did there come a point where you were
losing faith, but you basically had to
gaslight yourself
to continue to be effective, but you
were already slipping? Yeah.
It was after I returned from Pakistan.
I I spent
a year and a few months at headquarters
in a really, really great, important
position. I became the the executive
assistant to the CIA's Deputy Director
for Operations.
And in that position
It's a really tough job, but I had
access to literally everything that the
CIA was doing around the world.
Everything.
>> seem prudent
for anyone to have that.
Or is it necessary?
>> You have to brief the director and the
deputy directors. They can't get through
the 20,000 cables a day. Okay.
So you do it and you boil it down to the
five or six that they absolutely,
positively need to know about. And
that's challenging. It's very
challenging.
And I started seeing some of the other
things that we were doing around the
world.
And I thought to myself
why? Why are we doing that? To what end?
How does this help us?
How does this keep America safe?
I understand you want to be James Bond
or, you know,
GI Joe or whatever, kick asses and take
names. I I I get it. There are some guys
like that. I was never like that, but
there were some that I worked with. But
what does it gain for us?
And then when I went to my final
operational position,
I was um I was ordered to uh
to make a recruitment
that just didn't make operational sense.
It's like, why? Why are we Why are we
going to harass this guy?
"Because I'm ordering you to."
was the response.
And so I decided to slow roll it.
I I started having thoughts of
resigning.
And I thought, "You know what? I can
slow roll this to the point where I'm
going to resign before I need to make a
pitch." And so what I did is I just
continued taking the guy to dinner.
And all the time he thought we were
friends.
And that's how I left it.
And you never
told him you were from the State
Department. Oh, I told him I was from
the State Department.
>> Okay.
But that's what he That's what he
believes.
>> And then now he knows.
>> Now he knows. Now he knows, unless he
doesn't have Tik Tok.
>> those guys over the years, they're
probably like, "Oh, thank God he keeps
his mouth shut about the important
stuff." Yeah.
Which you do. Yeah. I mean, you're what
what we're getting is the tip of the
iceberg.
>> Oh, yeah, yeah.
>> Or you'd be back in prison.
>> Yeah, but I mean, morally I would never
reveal a Yeah. You don't want to put
anyone else in
>> no. And you never want to put anyone
else in jeopardy. No, never.
I want to um
talking about people in jeopardy.
We have I really my heart breaks where
there's a whole generation in jeopardy.
I would say Gen Z and the millennials.
I'm a father I have seven children five
I have four grandchildren.
AI is taking away their hopes of I'm a
filmmaker and a writer. I'm worried for
my career. I'm almost
>> Right. I can't imagine being a creative
>> too late for the poetry professors.
>> imagine being a creative writer. And my
haikus really improved
since ChatGPT. But, um
But, you know,
they have this. They have AI. They have
pornography and the apps destroying the
natural awakening of eros that all of us
had the experience of you know, the
first time you get excited around women
is at the pool.
You know, in eighth grade, you know, and
then you're like all the most beautiful
girls your age happen to be at that pool
that day. And you know, but now these
kids before that day ever comes, they've
been bombarded with pornography. Their
career dreams are being erased by AI. I
remember the '90s when we were like, "Oh
my gosh, our children are going to know
what a is because of Monica
Lewinsky, the Monica Lewinsky scandal."
12-year-olds, 10-year-olds, 8-year-olds
are searching the Epstein files right
now.
Then they see this war. They saw the
genocide in Gaza. Yep. And if you don't
want to call it a genocide, it is an
ethnic cleansing.
There is no debate on that. No one will
debate you on that.
>> cleansing is a form of genocide. So,
even if you don't acknowledge that
perhaps hundreds of thousands of people
have been have been killed,
it's still a genocide. And the Gen Z
sees this.
>> Yeah. They're Googling. They're going
through the Epstein files. They're
watching us yawn at a genocide. Um
they're watching men like you with
character and integrity. You were what
we're told we should all be.
You're the hero from the history books
today being persecuted. And now Tucker
Carlson is being threatened with
treason, which could be punishable, I
guess, up until death. I don't know what
they're thinking. But
and Gen Z has found you.
Yeah.
>> They found you. You didn't find them.
They found you.
>> glad and very grateful. What would you
say to them?
Yeah.
As they're witnessing Tucker Carlson
being crucified,
um
schools being bombed,
Lebanon being cleansed, Gaza being
cleansed, Christians in the West Bank
being persecuted.
And they're just sitting this and
they're just stunned. And they're like,
"I don't have a career. I'll never find
love.
And my parents and grandparents'
generation are crazy people."
>> Yeah.
Well, I mean,
at the risk of speaking in cliches,
you got to do the right thing. Listen,
if something feels wrong in your gut,
it's wrong. One of the things One of the
exceptions that I took with the CIA's
culture was the CIA always taught us
that everything was a shade of gray,
right? Everything in life is a shade of
gray. That is just simply not true. Gray
is what?
Gray is Is black and white.
>> It's black and white together.
>> is black and white.
>> black and white.
>> Yeah. The truth is some things are black
or white. They're either right or wrong.
And in our guts, we know what the right
thing to do is. So, do the right thing.
It Will there be a cost?
Probably, especially on these big-ticket
items, like genocide and ethnic
cleansing and murder,
targeted assassinations.
But, we know what the right thing to do
is. So, do it.
Do it and others will follow.
You know, there's there have have been
some uh
some
documentary examinations of uh 9/11 and
the aftermath. Now, we're in the 25th
year, right? It's going to be the 25th
anniversary of the 9/11 attacks this
year.
And
there was a
a series documentary series on Netflix
recently.
And it completely left me out.
It never mentioned me. They never
approached me. But, all of the actual
torturers
they interviewed.
And they were like, we had to do it. It
was the right thing to do. We saved
lives.
No, actually, you didn't.
>> believe they saved lives? No.
It's been categorically proven that they
didn't save lives. But the thing is that
>> cost less lives?
>> Well, the thing is, most likely.
In their obituaries
it's going to say that they were the
fathers of the torture program.
And the only thing that they can do
after all these years is just to repeat
that lie over and over and over and over
again and hope that they can convince
Americans
you know, in the fog of history
that they did the right thing. They
didn't do the right thing. And so I will
continue talking over and over again
until the day I die to ensure that
Americans have the truth.
You You asked the question a second ago
that deserves
a little bit of explanation.
When ISIS first began kidnapping
American journalists and executing them
when they beheaded them
the prisoners were always wearing orange
jumpsuits.
And it's because we made prisoners wear
orange jumpsuits.
They did that because of us. They
tortured Americans because we tortured
them.
So, you know
there's a cost and innocents pay the
price.
I want to
talk about innocents paying the price
for what our intelligence community
does. Where I work I'll often be accused
of of being CIA.
>> Sure.
>> Everywhere I go. Yeah, cuz people are
stupid. They're stupid
out there.
>> for them to use nonprofit organizations
to do their work.
>> And
do they? No.
When I was there, no. Journalists? No.
Not since '75. But they don't need to
recruit journalists. They control the
journalists already.
>> How do How do they control the
journalists?
>> Well, I'll tell you the story.
>> the NGOs, too, a lot of them?
>> some.
Through through funding. Okay, through
USAID? So, a friend of mine
Jason Shout out to Jason Leopold.
One of the finest journalists One of the
finest investigative journalists I've
ever encountered.
He has filed more Freedom of Information
Act requests than anybody else in the
world.
To the point where George W. Bush's
Pentagon spokesman called him a FOIA
terrorist.
They actually threatened him
because
he used the law
to get information released. He's the
one who broke the Hillary Clinton email
uh server story. You guys should like
start a super You know, like the like
the League of Justice. You're the human
rights guy, he's the FOIA terrorist, you
have a whole So, he told me that he was
bored
one week between Christmas and New Year.
And so, he filed a Freedom of
Information Act request just for the
heck of it
with the CIA, and he asked for
all communications between the CIA
and all American journalists
for a period of whatever it was, 2
years, 1 year, whatever it was.
And the CIA never ever responds. So, he
has
an attorney on uh
on call.
The law says they have to respond within
60 days. You're lucky if they respond
within 60 years. I'm serious.
And so, on day 61, they file a federal
lawsuit. He always wins, and the CIA
always has to pay his legal fees. Okay.
So, he he sues for this information.
>> this guy. All communications between the
CIA and all American journalists. Most
of it was
99% of it was garbage. It was, "Hey, I'd
like to uh get your opinion on such and
such. Oh, I'd like to interview the
director." Okay, who cares? But, what he
found was
Ken Dilanian.
He's the chief national security
correspondent for NBC News and MS Now,
formerly
MSNBC.
He was writing articles and then sending
them to the CIA for clearance before
sending them to his own editor.
Is this okay, you guys? This is what I
want to say. Are you cool with it?
Cuz if you're not, just let me know and
I'll take stuff out.
What is that? Why was he doing that?
Just because he was friends to get
information? Sure. And and
they control him. I mean, it's it's a
method of control, but more
interestingly,
he found this young, hungry, independent
journalist who actually stumbled on
something important.
And he wrote to the CIA and he said, "I
wrote this story. I'm publishing
tomorrow. Do you have any comment?"
And they wrote back and they said, "So
help us God, if you publish this story,
you will never be invited to the CIA
Christmas party ever again, and we will
never ever give you a background
briefing."
And he killed his own story.
His own story. For a Christmas party.
So, they don't need to recruit
journalists anymore. They love bomb you.
Yeah.
They recruit you. Mhm.
Essentially, without it actually being
spoken. And this guy looks like he
recruited himself. He just wanted to be
in the cool crowd. Yeah, exactly.
So, what would you say to Tucker Carlson
right now? He must be feeling the heat.
He's going through what you went
through. I mean, this is unbelievable to
me.
>> I have deep respect for Tucker Carlson.
I consider him to be a friend.
And um
he's really
he's really in in the in the woods right
now.
Uh people are jumping up and down on
him. They're calling him anti-semite of
the year, one of these Jewish groups
called him.
They called me the the Israeli foreign
minister's political director in a in an
article in a scholarly journal a few
months ago called me noted anti-semite
John Kiriakou. I'm like,
what?
>> Well, we were talking earlier. I said
being an anti-semite used to mean
um you hated Jews.
>> Jews.
>> Today it means you refuse to hate Arabs
or Muslims.
>> That's what it is right there. So, I
said to Tucker, I said, I'm I'm noted
anti-semite John Kiriakou. He said,
that's nothing. He said, I'm anti-semite
of the year. And we had a little laugh
over it. So,
now he's being ostracized
by not just AIPAC and and the the
smaller Jewish political organizations
here in the United States, but by
a lot of mainstream political figures.
Ted Cruz being first among them, Lindsey
Graham a close second, both of whom I
consider to be
dangerous tools of Israel.
>> They're open trade I mean, look, they're
trade. They should be investigated. I
just saw Lindsey Graham on Fox. I don't
care about you, I care about Israel.
>> Yeah. Then move to Israel if you think
it's so great.
>> Yeah, run go to Israel.
>> Yeah.
So, um
you know, it's one thing to fight Ben
Shapiro
on X.
It's an entirely different thing to have
a criminal referral made against you to
the Justice Department accusing you of
treason and espionage and violating the
Foreign Agents Registration Act.
We thought when when this story first
broke, we thought this was the CIA
cuz they file crimes reports against
people every single day. I can't tell
you how many times I've had crimes
reports filed against me.
Um
we thought it was the CIA that did it.
That didn't really make sense to me, but
the conventional wisdom was that it was
the CIA. And Tucker certainly thought it
was the CIA. But then the very next day,
Laura Loomer came out and said, "Nope,
it was me. An instrument of Israel.
Yeah. Literally she should be literally
an instrument of the Israeli government.
>> she is she registered as a foreign I
mean, she must be registered, right?
>> be because God knows she's representing
Israeli interests in the United States.
Yeah.
>> It's unbelievable. So, should Tucker be
scared?
I would be.
Um
I would be because for the for the
simple reason that there are a lot of
crazy people out there.
You know, it's one thing to shoot up a
church or shoot up a synagogue or shoot
up a mosque.
It's another thing to, you know,
lie in wait for somebody like uh
happened to Charlie Kirk.
I mean, Tucker's very very high profile,
higher than Charlie ever was. Yeah. And
um you know, thank God he doesn't live
in Washington anymore where he'd be easy
to find.
But still, you know, I I worry for the
guy's safety.
Do you worry? Does he have any legal
jeopardy that he should be worried
about?
>> Oh. He said in his response
to all this that that
no, he doesn't think he is in any legal
jeopardy, but he said, "I have great
lawyers. I'm blessed with plenty of
money. I don't need money. So, I have,
you know,
great lawyers, but this is ridiculous.
It's meant to silence me," he said, "and
it's not going to silence me."
>> You know it's meant to silence
other people that may follow Tucker cuz
they know they're not going to silence
Tucker.
>> said the same thing to me. They said,
"You know, this this case is not about
John Kiriakou. This case is about
silencing literally anybody who may be
thinking of blowing the whistle on
waste, fraud, abuse, or threats to the
public health or public safety."
>> So, what would you say to a young
intelligence officers right now who
that they are afraid? Yeah. But, they
want to speak out. What would you How I
would say
start with the Inspector General's
office. If you get no satisfaction from
the Inspector General,
bite the bullet,
hire a lawyer,
and do what your lawyer tells you to do.
That may mean going public.
Go to the Inspector General,
the oversight committees,
but if you get no satisfaction, you have
to go public. See, my my case was
unusual in that
I First, they say go through your chain
of command. I couldn't. My chain of
command created the torture program.
I couldn't go to the Inspector General
because this was so highly
compartmentalized
that the Inspector General wasn't read
into the program. And the Inspector
General had no idea.
>> a lot of programs he's not read into?
>> Yeah, lots.
He doesn't have a need to know. Mhm.
I couldn't go to the General Counsel cuz
the General Counsel had approved of the
torture program.
I couldn't go to the oversight
committees because they financed the
torture program.
So, where was I going to go? I could
only go to the media.
And sometimes,
that's what you do.
The day before you went to the media,
were you was that a Were you wavering or
you knew?
>> No.
No, the week before,
several things happened on
on Monday,
there was a presidential press
conference.
And
the president It wasn't a Monday, it was
a Wednesday. The president looked right
in the camera
in response to a question, and he said,
"We do not torture."
Like that.
And I said to my wife, she was a senior
CIA officer, I said, "He's a bald-faced
liar."
He's looking the American people in the
eye and he's just lying to us.
And then
2 days later, it was a Friday and he
came out of the White House through the
South Portico to walk to the
presidential helicopter, Marine One, to
go to Camp David for the weekend. And
you know, reporters always shout
questions when the president's doing
that walk from the South Portico to the
helicopter.
And somebody shouted about torture and
he stopped. And he said, "Well, if there
is torture, it's because of a rogue CIA
officer." Well, Brian Ross had called me
from ABC News the week before.
And he said he had a source who said
that I had tortured Abu Zubaydah. I said
that was absolutely wrong.
>> rogue officer torturing people.
And that's what I said to my wife.
Brian Ross's sources at the White House
and they're going to try to pin this on
me.
So, I called him and I said, "I'll give
you your interview."
And so, I decided in that week before
the interview that whatever he asked me,
I was just going to tell the truth
and just let the cards fall.
And so, that's what I did.
And here we are.
Millions of kids are watching you on
TikTok.
>> Yeah.
They didn't see that coming. They did
not see that coming. They also didn't
see Like they don't get you. They don't
get Tucker. They don't get people
>> They also didn't see John McCain
standing on the floor of the Senate and
saying that the American people owe John
Kiriakou a debt of gratitude because
without him, they would never have known
what the CIA was doing in their name.
>> that. God bless John McCain. He was an
interesting character.
Interesting.
>> could There's a lot to disagree with
John McCain on.
But on torture, there was nobody
>> air. I'll tell you off air something he
did for me that was unbelievable.
>> Well, I after I blew the whistle, I I
went to work for the Senate Foreign
Relations Committee. I worked for John
Kerry. And in the Russell Senate Office
Building, his his office was next to
McCain's. So, every time
Kerry and I would be walking out of the
office, McCain would be walking out of
his office. It was usually for a vote.
And he would say, "John Ciriacy, how are
you today?" And put out his hand.
And I'd say, "Senator, so good to see
you. Always good to see you." And he
always would give me a hearty handshake.
And finally, Kerry said to me one day,
"Why don't you and McCain get a room or
something?" And I said, "No, no, he's
he's serious. This is all about
torture." Cuz he knows.
>> He knows.
Yeah. And then and then
when I got out of prison,
one of the first phone calls I received
was from McCain's chief of staff.
He called me and he said, "Senator
McCain says, congratulations, welcome
home, and how can he be helpful?"
And I said, "These Obama took
my pension.
I'd really love to get my pension back."
So, my attorney and I went up to Capitol
Hill, and we came up with this plan.
My attorney wrote an amendment.
He wrote an amendment that was so
beautifully worded. It was just a couple
of sentences. And it said, "Every
American
convicted of violating the Intelligence
Identities Protection Act
between October 1st and October 31st,
2012,
shall hereby have his pension
reinstated."
So, of course, that's me. I'm the only
person in the world.
>> Yes.
And McCain said, "Look, we're going to
attach this to the National Defense
Authorization Act, the Pentagon budget,
cuz it's like 8,000 pages long." He
said, "We're going to slip it in down
here." He goes, "Nobody reads those
things. We'll slip it in down here.
I'll get myself appointed to the
conference committee because the House
and the Senate have to have to confer
and make sure that the two versions of
the bill are exactly the same, and then
it goes back for vote." He said, "I'll
get myself appointed to the conference
committee so that I can ensure that it
remains in the bill and then when the
president signs it it has the effect of
a pardon.
I was like, God bless you Senator
McCain.
And then he got brain cancer.
Oh, so this didn't go through. You
didn't get your pension. They took it
out of the took it out of the bill.
And so I never got the pension and then
he died.
You know, he was a hawk but
>> Yeah. but he he was He was right on
torture.
>> and and he was right on torture and you
know his daughter right now He was
honest.
>> Let's move to Iran because his his
daughter has been critical of the Trump
administration this war in Iran
especially the rhetoric.
>> it on the chin for this too on on X. So
Iran where by the way we're we're got a
storm barreling down. I have a lot of I
feel the gun like I've got all these
questions and I don't want John to be
stuck in the storm. How much time do we
have John do you think?
>> 1:05.
>> What did I tell you how when I said we'd
get you out of here by 1 Yeah. 15? We're
good. Okay, I don't want you to be I
don't want you to be
we're stranded here all together. Uh I
think it'll start just as I get here.
We're expecting like 75 mile an hour
winds and tornadoes. It's going to be
pretty bad.
>> like there's so much to ask you. Um
but I want to bring it to Iran because
everything is at stake in Iran.
And um Yes.
I feel like we this is the biggest
military blunder
in the history of the United States of
America.
When you look at how much trouble we had
in Afghanistan and Iraq
there is no comparison. No.
Or how do we actually what what would
you tell the President of the United
States? How do we act and and and in
fairness the intelligence community it
seems from leaks Mhm. said don't do
this.
>> Don't do this. Can't win it.
And they were ignored. Benjamin
Netanyahu convinced the president that
Iran was a house of cards
and as soon as the first missile was
launched it would collapse on top of
itself. And everybody would live happily
ever after. And anybody
>> Has that happened? Is that what's
happening now?
This is
just bad no matter how you look for.
First of all, it shows that
that well, George Galloway, the the
British parliamentarian, I love George.
Great guy. He said something last night
that was so true and funny at at the
same time and sad at the same time. He
said Benjamin Netanyahu has not been
seen in 2 weeks, which is true. Since
the hostilities began Netanyahu's been a
ghost. And he said
if Netanyahu is in hiding, who's running
the United States?
>> that. That's funny. Yeah.
>> And he's he's right. Because
our foreign policy is essentially
whatever Netanyahu says it's going to
be.
>> it's Laura Loomer. Which is even worse.
Which is even worse.
>> the United States.
>> Yeah. You know, there are times where
American foreign policy and Israeli
foreign policy intersect. Great.
There There is an old saying that
there's no such thing as permanent
friends, just permanent interests.
>> Yes.
>> But we have forgotten that in the case
of Israel.
Sometimes it is in American interest to
support Israel. Sometimes it's not.
This is one of those times when it's
not. I have five children, you have five
children. I don't want my children to
die for Israel.
>> fought My oldest son fought in Iraq and
Syria. I worked for Buchanan. I opposed
the invasion of Iraq and my son ended up
fighting ISIS. Incredible. God bless
him.
>> And I have boys barreling towards
military age now.
>> See?
And they're talking about the draft.
>> And they're talking about the draft. And
I'll tell you another thing. I had
dinner with a with a friend of mine the
other night who is a
longtime and full professor of history
at a major university, right? A
household name university.
And he said, because this is how well
connected he is at the Pentagon,
he said, "There is a real danger that
nuclear weapons are going to be used in
this fight." And he said, "On the one
hand,
at the Pentagon, they're afraid that
Donald Trump is considering using
nuclear weapons because it is what Trump
has called the last taboo.
And he wants to break that taboo to make
it okay for future presidents to use
nuclear weapons.
On the other hand,
I mentioned him, actually. I said, "I've
It's my understanding that the Israelis
have between 80 and 150 nuclear
warheads." He said, "I think the number
is more like 120 to 250 nuclear
warheads." And I made a comment that
about them being at Dimona. He said,
"They're not at Dimona. Dimona's where
the uranium is enriched. They're in a
deep underground bunker
west of Jerusalem."
Um he said,
"Can an Iranian hypersonic
do damage to that? Probably.
So, do the Israelis launch a nuclear
strike against Iran before the Iranians
can launch a hypersonic missile?
That's what they're afraid of at the
Pentagon.
There are two different ways in which
nuclear weapons could be used in this
conflict. I think that if If I were an
advisor to the president, I would say
this. I'd say, "Declare victory and come
home."
Right?
>> bases in all in the region or how far
would we go back?
>> you know what? We may not even have to
make that decision. The Arab Gulf
countries of the GCC, the Gulf
Cooperation Council, may make that
decision for us. The Gulf Cooperation
Council is Saudi Arabia, Kuwait,
Bahrain, Qatar, Oman, and the United
Arab Emirates. Okay.
So, there are about 50,000 troops at
bases in Saudi Arabia, Kuwait,
the UAE, and Oman at any given time,
just normally.
Qatar hosts the world's largest
air force base, that is Al Udeid air
force base, the biggest one we have
anywhere on the planet.
Bahrain is home to the fifth fleet,
which is the naval component of Central
Command, which is itself based in at
MacDill
MacDill in outside Tampa.
So, every one of these GCC countries
hosts army, navy, air force, and
Marines.
And all those American personnel
couldn't stop the Iranians from sending
$10,000 drones laden with explosives.
>> We've done a better job of protecting
Israel Yeah.
>> than we have of protecting our own
troops.
>> Yes. If this doesn't make the American
public furious
>> not even just our own troops.
The Iranians are hitting hotels in
Dubai. They blew up a a fuel storage
tank at Dubai Airport today, the busiest
airport in the world, and it's closed.
They hit an oil refinery in Saudi
Arabia. They've hit the the runways of
both Kuwait International Airport and
Bahrain International Airport.
>> How have they done this? Haven't we
defeated them seven times in the past 2
weeks? Yeah. I thought they'd been
defeated. Everything's There's no more
targets. There's no more targets.
>> we've bombed them to the Stone Age,
right? I mean, that's what that's what
we're supposed to believe.
>> Are you hopeful that this war is going
to end soon?
>> No.
The Israelis won't allow it to end soon.
And we do what the Israelis tell us to
do.
>> So, how does this end? How does this
Where does this go? Look what's
happening in Lebanon, the West Bank.
We have a campaign at Vulnerable People
Project called
savewestbankchristians.com.
I I I I was I spent Christmas in the
West Bank. I spent a lot of time in the
West Bank. We work in Gaza. We work with
the Christian community and the orphan
community in Gaza.
I'm very close to the
Every morning, the first thing I do and
every night, first thing I do before I
go to bed is I check in on the people
that work with me in the West Bank
and they're scared.
Um, increased settler violence right
under our nose, the specific targeting
of Taybeh, a Christian village.
Um, they just approved a new settlement
Shepherds where they're going to drop
11,000 Christian homes which will
effectively end Christians in Bethlehem
and and and and Shepherds field.
And we have an ambassador
who was a pastor
and he signed on to these abuses. He's
as much a part of the problem as any
Zionist politician, Israeli politician.
You know, when he welcomed the traitor
Jonathan Pollard into the American
Embassy and feted him like a hero after
Pollard said that Israelis should take
up arms against the United States.
That was enough for me.
The Am- Ambassador Friedman should have
resigned on the spot. He doesn't have
the
big balls
to resign. He has no honor.
And then the whole
Tucker Carlson interview where he
essentially said, "Yeah, I I pretty much
represent the Israeli government. I
think the Israelis should take all of
the Middle East.
Just take it." Mike Johnson went to the
settlements outside of Bethlehem and met
with the settlers
to give them a rah-rah speech.
He didn't meet with the Christians that
have been there since the first century.
>> Yeah.
Yeah.
And but the American public is waking up
to this. So, we have this campaign
savewestbankchristians.com
and we're really going to focus
attention on the West Bank this Easter
because they increase the abuses on
Christians around on around the treaty.
And we're going to really try to do our
best to make sure everyone's paying
attention to this. Um, do you think that
this administration will res- be
responsive? Trump has said many times no
more settlements in the West Bank.
Israel responds by saying, "Here's a new
settlement right in the Christian area."
And we're going to drop 11,000 homes.
Donald Trump
will do literally nothing to help
Christians
in Palestine. But neither did Joe Biden
or Barack Obama or George W. Bush or
George H.W. Bush or Ronald Reagan or
anybody else.
Because the Israelis control our foreign
policy.
And we do as they tell us to do.
How do we extricate ourselves from their
influence?
The very first thing we need to do is to
force AIPAC to register as a foreign
agent. It's It's a bad joke that AIPAC
is just a bunch of concerned Americans
who support Israel.
Please. It's an insult to to the
intelligence of every American.
AIPAC needs to register just like
everybody else needs to register.
And then we need to put America first.
You know, I I approached this whole
America first thing in the MAGA movement
from the political left.
And I was a true believer.
I I really want us to put America first.
>> I campaigned
this past cycle
in Pennsylvania where I met with the
Syrian Christians in the Lehigh Valley.
I met with the Muslim community.
And I really organized them to support
the president because I said he has
given us his word. He is going to end
this war. He said He said there's too
many Palestinians dying. This has to
stop.
And it's
>> He said all the right things.
>> all the right things.
>> did all the wrong things. You know,
another thing too, I've said this many
times, but but
every Israeli prime minister going back
to the Reagan administration, every
prime minister on every visit to
Washington has asked the president,
"Please bomb Iran. Please bomb Iran.
Please bomb Iran." And every president
has said no until this one.
The one that has for a decade
been ridiculing the idea of bombing
Iran.
Right. Oh my gosh, the terrible things
he said about Barack Obama.
You know, that he's weak and he doesn't
know how to negotiate and the only
reason we're talking about bombing Iran
is cuz he can't negotiate. And then, you
know, like somebody said to me the other
day, "There's always a tweet."
And it's true. It's the the the one uh
uh
Olympic hockey player, female, she said,
"Trump always
undoes
all the good thing he does." I think is
the quote. Or he
undoes all the good he does. Something
like that. It was very interesting It
was an interesting quote and that's how
I feel.
Yeah.
>> and I'm sitting here and I'm looking
what's happening in Lebanon. The ethnic
cleansing has now moved to Lebanon.
You know, under George W. Bush we saw
the erasure of the ancient Christian
communities in Iraq. Then under Obama we
saw it in Syria.
>> Yes. And now we're seeing it in Lebanon
and we're going to see it in the Holy
Land. And the church in America is
silent. And it's really your community.
It's the Orthodox
>> The Orthodox that are suffering the
most. Yeah. Yeah, they really are. It's
interesting that Gen Z now the
Protestants, evangelicals are panicked
because Gen Z is They're all becoming
either Orthodox or I have to imagine
Orthodox churches now are are filled
with a bunch of of like young
Anglo kids.
>> Yes, it's true. The The New York Times
had an article just recently over the
last three or four weeks about this mass
migration from evangelical churches to
um the Orthodox church. But there were
There were articles in the major
newspapers 10 and 20 years ago saying
that more evangelical Christians are
converting to Orthodoxy than to any
other denomination. And it's because
they feel this need for tradition and a
respect for tradition.
>> Liturgy, beauty.
>> Liturgy. You know, the Orthodox church
I mean this quite literally. The
Orthodox church has not changed since
453 AD.
We we still use
we call it church Greek. It's like
church Slavonic or church Arabic where
it's not modern Greek that's spoken. And
even the English cuz now it's half
English, half Greek or all English.
It's not even like modern spoken
English. It's that kind of old school,
you know, biblical English.
>> I mean that you can go to Orthodox
communities where it's still in Aramaic.
It's still in Aramaic.
>> The Assyrians.
>> Absolutely true.
Uh but I will say when I was growing up,
you mentioned
>> needs to tell them their theology.
Huckabee's going to sit there and
lecture the ancient Christian
communities
>> Huckabee's going to teach them
>> that their theology is replacement
theology. You're replacement theology.
Well, where did your theology come from?
>> truth, I'm I'm going to make people
angry by saying this, but I don't care.
I'm going to say it anyway.
This this Huckabee style evangelical
Christianity, we consider we Orthodox
consider to be a cult. I think it's
apostasy.
>> It is apostasy. If you deny that Jesus
doesn't fulfill the promises of it's
actually anti-Semitic. And we don't even
It's very anti-Semitic.
>> Agreed. It others them. Yes.
>> Permanently others them.
>> Mhm. Which Jesus ended the othering of
the human family, which is what makes
our faith so beautiful.
Yes. I I wanted to make a point. You
mentioned Lehigh and meeting with Syrian
Christians in Lehigh. I come from
Newcastle, Pennsylvania on the other
side of the state and we had have still
a large robust Antiochian community.
They were Syrian and Lebanese immigrants
from the turn of the 20th century into
the 1930s. Um and so the Syrians that
came to Newcastle to work in the mills
were Syrian Christians for the most
part. Um so when I was a little kid, you
know, we always had this pan-Orthodox.
It was the Greeks we were the the
biggest and then the Antiochian
>> festivals were the best.
>> Festivals were the best. And the
Antiochians, the Russians, the
Ukrainians, the Serbs, the Bulgarians,
the Romanians if I didn't say Romanians.
So, we all had our own churches. Many of
them are closed now. The Russians, the
Serbians, the
the Romanians, the Bulgarians, their
churches have closed. But,
the Antiochian Church on the east side,
on Lynn Street, it is
enormous
because of all these converts.
That's really something else.
>> I came in through atheism into I was
evangelical for like a month.
And then I realized I had go Orthodox or
Catholic. I really wanted to go
Orthodox, but I was it was I was on that
line and I thought I'm Irish and
Scottish and I was strange at Greek Fest
and I studied I studied the schism and
to me I agree with St. John Paul the
Great that the church will never breathe
with both lungs until east and west are
together and
>> Yeah. I believe that the western church
and the eastern church it is. I don't
it's not that I believe. It's the
church. And they've made great progress
in reunification. They started talks on
reunification in 1965.
So, they've been going on for some time
now. We're going on 61 years.
>> it happens I'm going to take credit cuz
for my first communion I was an adult
convert in my 30s.
The priest said, "You know, your first
communion
it's very powerful when you first time
you receive the Eucharist. So, make make
a prayer and it will happen." And so, I
didn't want my sister who's Greek to go
to the Roman Catholic Church in Chicago
cuz it was dead.
But, I knew that I it was probably
inappropriate as a Catholic to pray for
her to become Greek Orthodox, but I did.
I My first communion was that she would
become Greek Orthodox, that the Orthodox
Church would come into union with Rome,
and that abortion would end. Those were
my three prayers. I will say Roe v. Wade
overturned. The day that I received my
first communion union, my sister didn't
know this was happening. I called her to
tell her what I did and she before I
could say anything she goes, "Bradley,
you'll never guess what I did today. I
signed up for Greek school catechism
class at the Greek Church." And now she
is Eastern Catholic. But,
she still participates in the Orthodox
Orthodox liturgy. When you were
um
working in the in the CIA, did you go to
confession? Mhm. How did you handle
confessions? I mean, that had Is there a
process or Yeah, if confessions in the
Orthodox church are a little bit
>> I mean, can you can't confess everything
you're doing, obviously. No, but the
priest knew
where I worked. I mean, I wasn't the
only CIA guy at St. Catherine's Greek
Orthodox Church in Falls Church,
Virginia. Do they make sure those those
they're not bugged?
>> I mean, if I was the foreign
intelligence agency, I would be bugging.
>> in that we go into the confessionals.
You look face-to-face.
>> You sit there and you look the guy right
in the eye and you say, "Father, I did
this, I did that, I did this, I did
that."
>> Did they ever gasp or just go, "What in
the world?"
>> No.
I mean, the hummus story, did they not
Did you confess the hummus?
>> Oh, I didn't do that.
Okay, I don't know it. I only know it
secondhand. Oh, no, no. I had nothing
>> But you knew of it.
>> years after I left. No, no. It was in
the Senate torture report. Can we
address that? I want you to finish the
confession because we talked about how
the young kids are responding to this
because they're scandalized and this is
a coping mechanism. I want to end maybe
end with that and one other question,
but but if I have finished with the
confession thing.
>> the the priest is used to dealing with
CIA people. So, you can speak in
generalities and that's That's fine.
>> He knows what you're trying to what
you're trying to do.
>> Um, in Greece
>> Forgive me, Father, for I sinned. I was
rough with a client this week.
>> Is that a good confession?
>> That's a good confession. In Greece,
it's different. You look them right in
the eye and they read a list of sins.
And you have to say, "Yeah, I did that."
>> that better.
>> do that. That's better. Uh-huh.
That seems easier.
>> It's It's I mean, I went to confession
yesterday. It's I mean, you know, I've
been Catholic 25 years. It's still not
easy. Yeah, it's not easy.
So, hummus, we should talk about this.
>> Yeah, you know, it's young people. It's
become a meme. Well, it And you know,
they're scandalized and they And you
know, when you I remember when I was a
young boy trying to impress my friends.
We'd watch this this TV this VHS we had
called Faces of Death.
>> Faces of Faces of Death.
>> And they had one, two,
three and we'd laugh.
>> Yeah. I remember watching Clockwork
Orange and we'd laugh. But like inside I
was grimacing. Inside I was like really
uncomfortable. But we'd be laughing and
watch it again and so I think all of Gen
Z now is watching this hummus video
which I really know nothing about. My
sons were just giving me the
the the cliff notes on it. And they've
made a joke out of it and I think the
joke is just like when we were watching
Faces of Death.
>> Yeah. Like
watch your mouth. You're going to get
some hummus up your butt.
>> Like I look at this horrible thing and
laugh at it cuz I'm a strong man. You
think that's what that is?
>> No, it's different.
>> Okay. Yeah. Um so I gave an interview a
couple of months ago to
a podcast called Diary of a CEO. Third
largest podcast on the planet. Very big
deal for me. Almost 10 million views.
And some kid
on TikTok took some of the stories that
I told on that podcast and cut them into
shorts.
>> First time I'm hearing all this. Okay,
good.
>> And he changed my voice. So for most of
the story it's in an Alvin and the
Chipmunks voice. And then when I say the
punchline of the story
it's this deep voice like this, you
know?
And I say I said in the podcast that
we know thanks to the Senate torture
report that one of the ways that Abu
Zubaydah was tortured was
the doctor said he was dehydrated and so
instead of giving him an IV
they shoved a tube up his rectum. And
then using a blood pump they pumped
hummus into his rectum. And I said, "Now
that's potentially fatal. That's That's
clearly illegal. Clearly illegal in
addition to being immoral and unethical.
But dangerous. Medically you can cause
organs to burst. right? And cause
instant sepsis and death.
And um
nobody was authorized to do something
like that.
>> When did you find out about that?
>> Senate torture report.
>> So you didn't know about it to No.
Because they never reported it. They
just did it.
And said, "Guys, just between us."
What were What were they You knew these
people. What were they thinking? What
were they thinking?
>> We We
socialized together. Our wives were
friends. Our children played together.
And they're monsters, it turns out.
>> But if you were to dinner party and you
slap them, they'd be horrified.
>> Horrified.
So I told the story and I said, "This is
It's all laid out in the Senate torture
report. You can see it there with your
own eyes." So what do you say to the
young people that are watching this and
they're laughing at it, but we know
they're not really You know, we know
when they're watching it and their
friends are sharing it and they're
laughing, but but really they're
scandalized at what kind of world have I
been born into? Yeah.
It's bad.
And you know, this was revealed in the
Senate torture report. You think anybody
did anything about it? You think anybody
went to prison? You think anybody
bothered to investigate?
All we ended up getting was
six or seven of the CIA torture uh
uh promoters wrote a little booklet,
little 90-page whatever it is a booklet
saying, "No, no, no, no, it's not
torture, but torture worked. It worked
and we saved American lives. We can't
tell you the details cuz it's
classified, but take our word for it.
And if you If you could see what we
could see
>> people we saved?
>> Yeah. Please.
I went to prison because I told the
truth about it. They're lying to you.
They're lying.
If anything, it cost American lives.
So they're lying to us, the American
people. And this is half of my audience
is in the Middle East. We have a very
large audience in Iraq and Excellent.
>> Um I was just recently I I I guess two
days ago I was in Kurdish uh
Iraqi Kurdish television.
What would you say to President Barzani?
What would you say to our allies that
are being baited into this war?
Yeah. We're lying to them, aren't we? I
mean, we're they're probably hearing
that.
>> to them.
God, I I have so much respect for the
Barzanis.
You know, going back to Masoud Barzani
and the
and the liberation of Kuwait.
I won't get into that, but anyway, I
have a very deep respect for the Barzani
family and the KDP and the PUK for that
matter.
Um,
they're lying to you.
We're not going to help Iran's Kurds.
There's not going to be an independent
Kurdistan.
Um, they're using you only because
you're a warm body who can hold a gun.
And um,
you know, they would rather you die than
an American soldier die. Don't believe
them. Don't sign on to this. It's a
no-win situation.
What pressure can we put on them to
force them to Are we Are we Are we
tightening the screws on them or We are
not, but we could. I hope we don't.
We could.
You know, the the Iraqi Kurds are very
fortunate in that as part of their um,
their autonomy agreement with the
central government in Baghdad,
they get some of the oil revenue. Much
of the oil fields in Iraq are in
northern Iraq.
And so, you know, the the Kurds, God
bless them, they they have kind of a
good thing going right now.
Better than the situation that the
Iranian Kurds or the Syrian Kurds are
in.
Don't upset the apple cart. The status
quo works.
Look what we did when they
Brett McGurk posted a picture when they
had the referendum in 2017.
Um, he posted a picture of him with
Iraqi soldiers standing under a sign
that said, "Erbil."
Threatening them.
We've never had their best interests.
>> Never. And they are they love the
American people.
>> And the Kurds are
some of the the kindest
people that you can encounter.
They they they're
they have a beautiful culture.
And
I don't know. They're just some of the
finest people that I've ever met in my
in my life. And I when I call my wife
when I'm in Iraqi Kurdistan you know,
she understands. You know, she hears my
voice. She goes, "We're not moving
there."
She hears it in my voice. By the way,
when I said the name Brett McGurk Yeah.
>> on your face was awesome. Now, we don't
we don't we don't have time to get into
that guy. I've always wanted to make a
documentary on that guy, but
Talk about a survivor, huh? He's a sur-
like a cockroach. Like a cockroach. Like
a cockroach.
>> The only thing that can survive a
nuclear war, the cockroach.
>> Is it true about the video on the roof
of the embassy and him?
That's my understanding.
And when we finish this and stop
recording, remind me to tell you
something else. Okay, I got some
stories, too. John, I don't want to be
the man responsible for you being stuck
in an ice storm.
You know, I greatly admire you. What I
am I couldn't be more grateful that Gen
Z has discovered you and they and
they're going to make a deep dive.
>> grateful for this. Very grateful. Yeah.
It's worth it. There's not a man in the
world I would want that generation
paying to more than to you and and
because you've
you've lived a noble, beautiful life.
You're a man of faith.
And you're someone that this Gen Z
generation can really look up to because
there's not They're looking up to a lot
of people because they say they do brave
things or they say true things, but
their lives are
they're a bewildering mix of
contradictions, a lot of their heroes.
And so to have just kind of a man who
lived a quiet life of integrity and hard
work um but was forced by circumstances
into the spotlight for them for Gen Z to
discover you is something I'm grateful
for. And And you were very generous. You
are literally the most in-demand man in
the world and you took time to come on
this this the rinky-dinky little outfit
that Jason Jones thanks John. Good to
see you man. Bless you brother.
>> Thank you and you. This episode as a
well how lucky are we to have John
Kiriakou here on this episode has been
brought you by the vulnerable people
project. The mission of the vulnerable
people project is to stand in solidarity
with the most vulnerable people in the
world when the world is left away from
the Yazidis in Iraqi Kurdistan to the
uyghurs in Chinese occupied East
Turkistan to the Christians and to the
general to all the Palestinians in the
West Bank and Gaza. Go to our website
vulnerablepeopleproject.com.
Look at what we're doing from the Nuba
Mountains of Sudan to Pakistan to Gaza.
Look at what we're doing. If you want to
be a part of it scroll up click on the
donate button and become a monthly
donor. All right guys, this is
I've never been nervous when I've done
an interview, but I was already nervous
and then we had a time we had the
snowstorm blizzard hurricane tsunami
Godzilla, whatever's coming for
Washington DC right now.
Um but until next time it's been the
Jason Jones show.